payubiz.in 2019-05-15

# Privacy Policy - PayUbiz Payment Gateway

PayU Payments Private Limited (“PayU”, “we”, “our” or “us”) recognizes the importance of protecting personal details and information and provides this Privacy Policy with respect to the access and use (direct or indirect) of www.payubiz.in (“Services”). For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, the user of Services may be merchants/sellers/billers, customers/buyers/consumers, or any other persons using Services (“User”, “you” or “your”). This Privacy Policy will help you understand our policies and procedures regarding the collection, handling and use of your information.

By using our Services through the Sites, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy and consent to the processing of your Information (Personal Information and/or Sensitive Personal Data or Information). If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy do not, in any manner, use our Services, install and/or use the mobile application.

**Information Collection**

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of your Information collected from (i) Merchants/ Sub-Merchants who use or may want to use our payment gateway services; and/or (ii) consumer information that we acquire in the course of our business.

As a merchant/ sub-merchant, we collect your Information, through the registration process, the service agreement that we execute and various submitted documents of your creditability that are required from time to time. We may ask customers to enter personal data when placing an order, such as name, address, phone number, credit card/ banking details and e-mail address and use this data to protect the merchant and ourselves against risk.

As a customer we capture your Profiling Information, Correspondence Information, domain name from which you contact us, the pages you request, the products you buy, the referring site, and the time that you spend on the site. For everyone who visits any of our merchant’s website/ purchase page, we log IP addresses, the type of operating system that your computer uses, and the type of browser software used by you. Further, we may also capture your Service Usage and Transactional Information; one-time passwords if you have consented for it; Correspondence Information; cookies, etc.

**Purpose**

We respect your privacy and want to promote trust and confidence on the internet. As such, we feel it is necessary to disclose to you what information this site collects and tracks and what we do with the information that we collect. We collect and use your Information, to send you updates, to improve our Services, to improve user experience, for quicker transactions, for risk checks, for strengthening our security checks, for analysis and for offering you new features in the existing services you are availing or offering altogether new product/ service which may be relevant for you. It is clarified that the Information of Users which has been collected by us or provided to us, is the property of PayU and we may use it, in whole or in part, in our sole discretion and without any compensation to you, for any legitimate purpose and you hereby confirm that you have no objection to the aforesaid use of your Information.

**Disclosure**

Information security is critical to our business. We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. We store information gathered on secure computers. We use advanced security technology to prevent our computers from being accessed by unauthorized persons. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your Login ID/password and to your computer. Be sure to protect the password used to access our services.

We use reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure and do not disclose this information to other individuals or organizations unless required for provision of Services to you such as to banks, card associations, . However we will exchange information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and risk reduction. You acknowledge and agree that for the purpose of sending you updates/ communications, improving product, personalisation, offering new features in the existing services you are availing, offering new products/ services which may be relevant for you and Service efficiency, we may, under controlled and secure circumstances, share your Information with our affiliates, associates or third parties with whom we have an legal arrangement in place.

We assure you that we do not use such your Information for marketing purposes unless we receive your express consent.

We may disclose your Information pursuant to applicable laws, a directive or order of a government entity or statutory authority or any judicial or regulatory authority or to law enforcement agencies in any official investigation including but not limited to cyber incidents, prosecution and punishment of offences. You agree that PayU has the right to monitor and to disclose Information as may be necessary to satisfy any law, regulation or other governmental request. We may transfer Your Information or other information collected, stored, processed by PayU to any other entity or organization located in India or outside India only in case it is necessary for providing Services to You in connection with Application. We will cooperate with the appropriate law enforcement authorities in investigating claims of illegal activity.

We will only disclose your Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If we want to use it for any other purpose, we will obtain your consent.

If you decline to submit Information to us, then we will unfortunately not be in a position to provide the Services to you.

**Security**

We work to protect the security of your Information during transmission by using appropriate software, which encrypts information you input. This encrypted information is stored on secure systems/computers. We use advanced security technology to prevent our computers from being accessed by unauthorized persons.

We have also implemented information security practices and standards and have in place information security programmes and policies containing managerial, technical, operational and physical security measures that are in compliance with the Indian laws including, so as to protect the your Information with us us from unauthorized access, use, modification, damage, disclosure or impairment. In fact we have received ISO 27001 certification.

However, no data transmission over the internet is fully secure, so we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you submit to us. Further, we do not guarantee in any way, the security of any Information that you transmit or share on the Site; and you do so at your own risk.

We urge you to keep your Information confidential and not share it with anyone unless necessary. Any of your information which you provide when you use our Services to an open, public environment or forum including (without limitation) any blog, chat room, community, classifieds or discussion board, (a) will not be considered confidential, (b) will not be

considered as Personal Information, and (c) is not subject to protection under this Privacy Policy. Since such public environments are accessible by third parties, it is possible that third parties may collect or use such information for their own purposes. In the case of abuse or breach of security, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties which receive the information illegally. We will not distribute customer information to be used in mailing lists, surveys, or any other purpose other than what is required to perform our services.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

PayU reserves the right to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time for any reason. In case, any changes are made in the Privacy Policy, PayU shall update the same on the website. Users should periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. Once posted, those changes are effective immediately, unless stated otherwise. Continued access or use of the Services constitutes your acceptance of the changes and the amended Privacy Policy. However, if you do not agree with the changes, please do not continue to use the Services or submit Personal Information to us.

**Changes to your Information**

If you (i.e. our Merchant) would like to view the information we have collected from you and your customers or you want to correct your information or the billing/shipping details of your customers or their IP addresses, please go to Merchant Login page and log into your account to view the above details and to review your Information. If you have questions or suggestions, we can be reached by email at privacy@payu.in.

If you are a customer, and would like to view the information we have collected from you or you want to correct your information or details, please send us your request by email on privacy@payu.in.

The User can at any time withdraw his/her consent given previously to PayU for collecting, receiving, possessing, storing, dealing or handling Information of the User, by sending us your request by email on privacy@payu.in. In such case, PayU will unfortunately not be in a position to provide the Services to you. However, PayU will be able to retain such Information for the time period in accordance with the applicable laws.

**Disclaimer**

We reserve the right to report any illegal activity by any User, that is, our -Merchants or their customers to law enforcement for prosecution. Please be aware that we do not control the acts of our Sub-Merchants, customers or visitors.

Contacting PayU Please feel free contact us at contact@payu.in to highlight any issues that you may be facing or require any information/ assistance from us. In case you have any grievance relating to the collecting, receiving, possessing, storing, dealing or handling of Personal Information provided by you, you may contact our Grievance Officer at the following address:

Attn: Mr. Prashanth Susarla,

The Grievance Officer,

PayU Payments Private Limited,

9th Floor, Bestech Business Tower, Sohna Road, Sector 48, Gurgaon - 122002,

Haryana, India Phone: 0124-6786285
